Guide to the Hendricks Family Papers, 1713-1976 (bulk 1755-1959) MS 295
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Hendricks Family and Partnership Business Records (1794-1928), 7900
  - Subseries III.C. Soho Copper Company and Belleville Copper Rolling Mill Business and Property Records, 8098
    The subseries contains deeds, mortgages, indentures, contracts, maps, blueprints, photographs, and other records from the Belleville mill and property and is organized chronologically by subject and form.
    - Deeds, mortgages, indentures 1794-1861, 8126 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Deeds, mortgages, indentures, 1876-1912; 8127 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Deeds and agreements: mining and cotton mill, 1807-1874; 8128 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Maps, blueprints, descriptions, 1809-1911; 8129 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Belleville homestead: deeds, maps, mortgages, 1820-1911; 8130 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Belleville Lead Company: deeds, maps, mortgages, and related documents, [1847-1862]; 8131 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Property appraisal, 1905; 8132 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Deeds, indentures, mortgages, mining agreements, 1794-1848; 8275 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 7)
    - Deeds, maps, mortgages, blueprints, 1794-1890s; 8277 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 8)
    - Photographs, including homestead, Undated; 8278 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Henricks 9)
    - Mounted photograph, Undated; 8279 (Drawer Unfiled)
- Series IV. Hendricks Properties Records (1794-1911), 7901
  The series contains deeds, mortgages, indentures, contracts, maps, and blueprints for various properties owned by members of the Hendricks family in New York City and New Jersey, excluding Belleville. The material is organized chronologically and by individual property, whenever possible.
  - Various Hendricks properties, 1774-1864; 8133 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Specific properties, 1802-1902; 8134 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Abstracts, contracts, title papers, 1837-1840s; 8135 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Homestead deeds, mortgages, indentures, 1816-1847; 8280 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 10)
  - Deeds, mortgages, leases, 1815-1861; 8282 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 11)
  - Deeds, mortgages, survey/map, 1803-1863; 8281 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 12)
  - Deeds, maps, mortgages, 1807-1827; 8283 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 13)
- Series V. Hendricks and Related Families Personal Papers (1713-1966), 7902
  This series contains the personal papers of members of several generations of the Hendricks family and other families related to them by marriage, in the form of personal papers, correspondence, wills, marriage contract, and other religious and legal documents, photographs, and memorabilia. It also contains genealogical research and notes, charts, stamps, coats-of-arms, and other background information.
  The records describe the Hendricks family's involvement in the social, religious, and economic life of the city. Member of the Hendricks family were leaders of synagogue Shearith Israel, the Jewish Benevolent Society, and the American Jewish Historical Society. Members of several related families, such as Edwin Einstein, husband of Uriah Hendricks's daughter Fanny and candidate for mayor in the early 1900s, became involved in political life. Given the extent of intermarriage with other prominent New York Jewish families and the Hendricks's position as community leaders, the material in this series contains a wealth of information on the New York Jewish community and New York society in general, from the late eighteenth to the mid-twentieth centuries.
  For additional material, see Series IX. Hendricks and Related Families Supplement (1790-1976).
  The material is organized into 10 subseries by family, beginning with Harmon and his children, followed by his grandchildren's generation, and then alphabetically by family name and chronologically by birth order within that.
  Subseries V.A. Family of Harmon and Frances (Isaacs) Hendricks
  Subseries V.B. Family of Uriah II and Fanny (Tobias) Hendricks
  Subseries V.C. Family of Henry and Harriet (Tobias) Hendricks
  Subseries V.D. Family of Montague and Rachel (Brandon) Hendricks
  Subseries V.E. Hendricks Grandchildren Generation
  Subseries V.F. Gomez Families
  Subseries V.G. Families H-L
  Subseries V.H. Nathan Family
  Subseries V.I. Families S-W
  Subseries V.J. Notes, Clippings, Correspondence and Visual Material
  - Subseries V.A. Family of Harmon and Frances (Isaacs) Hendricks, 7979
    Related Archival Materials
    See Subseries IX.A. Early Hendricks family material, 1790-1866.
    Inserted before the folders is a list of the children of Harmon and Frances Isaacs Hendricks.
    - Sally Hendricks (sister of Harmon), 1805; 8137 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Frances (Isaacs) Hendricks (wife of Harmon), 1806-1844; 8138 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Henrietta "Hetty" and Aaron Gomez (daughter and son-in-law), 1820-1865; 8139 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Uriah Hendricks, II (son), 1828-1869; 8140 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Uriah Hendricks, II (son): letterbook for estate of mother, Undated; 8141 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Fanny (Tobias) Hendricks (wife of Uriah II), 1869-1881; 8142 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Henry Hendricks (son) 1839-1887, 8143 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Harriet (Tobias) Hendricks (wife of Henry), 1868-1929; 8144 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Washington Hendricks (son), 1810, 1841; 8145 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Montague Hendricks (son), Undated; 8146 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Emma (or Emily) (Hendricks) Nathan (daughter; wife of Benjamin), Undated; 8147 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Hannah (Hendricks) Hart (daughter; wife of Benjamin), 1840; 8148 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Rosalie (Hendricks) Tobias (daughter) 1839-1844, 8149 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Selina Hendricks (daughter) 1839-1887, 8150 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Uriah II deeds; Washington items; Rosalie items, 1837-1911; 8284 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 14)
    - Uriah Hendricks, II, estate: account book, 1869-1881; 8151 (Volume 16)
    - Rosalie Hendricks: composition book, 1834 September; 8152 (Volume 17)
  - Subseries V.B. Family of Uriah II and Fanny (Tobias) Hendricks, 7980
    - Joshua Hendricks (son), 1840-1879; 8153 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Uriah II: group photograph of his 11 daughters, Undated; 8154 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Joshua Hendricks (son) 1880-1904, 8155 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Joshua Hendricks (son): photos and ephemera, Undated; 8156 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Emma (Brandon) Hendricks (wife of Joshua), 1904; 8157 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      See Subseries IX.A. Early Hendricks family material.
    - Edmund Hendricks (son), 1861-1907; 8158 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Francis Hendricks (son), 1856-1902; 8159 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Helen Ida Hendricks (daughter), 1915; 8160 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Harmon W. Hendricks (son), 1869-1928; 8161 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Edith Hendricks (daughter), 1920; 8162 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Fanny (Hendricks) Einstein (daughter; wife of Edwin), 1903; 8163 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Isabel Emily (Hendricks) Brush (daughter), 1906, 1915; 8164 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Blanche (Hendricks) Hendricks (daughter; wife of Harmon II), 1877-1913; 8165 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Francis Hendricks diploma; Harmon Hendricks SPCA certificate; Edmund item; Francis item, 1861, 1912, undated; 8294 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 14)
    - Blanche Hendricks: composition book, 1866-1868; 8166 (Volume 18, Folder unknown container)
  - Subseries V.C. Family of Henry and Harriet (Tobias) Hendricks, 7981
    - Isaac Hendricks (son), 1870-1887; 8167 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Justina L. (Hendricks) Henry (daughter), 1856; 8168 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Eleanor Hendricks (daughter), 1886, 1909; 8169 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Rosalie (Hendricks) Allen (daughter; wife of Henry S.), 1875, 1887; 8170 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Arthur Tobias Hendricks (son), 1861, 1890; 8171 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Irene (Hendricks) Henriques (daughter; wife of Clarence), 1870-1922; 8172 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Subseries V.D. Family of Montague and Rachel (Brandon) Hendricks, 7982
    - Mortimer Hendricks (son), 1865; 8173 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Harmon Hendricks, II (son), 1877, 1894; 8174 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Subseries V.E. Hendricks Grandchildren Generation, 7983
    - Ethel Hendricks (daughter of Harmon II and Blanche), 1911; 8175 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Edgar Hendricks (son of Joshua and Emma), 1873-1894; 8176 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Lillian (Henry) Hendricks (wife of Edgar), 1928; 8177 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      See Subseries IX.B. Lilian (Henry) Hendricks.
    - Henry H. Hendricks (son of Joshua and Emma), 1869-1904; 8178 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Clifford B. Hendricks (son of Joshua and Emma), 1890-1901; 8179 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Henry S. Hendricks (son of Edgar and Lillian), 1949-1959; 8180 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      See Subseries IX.C. Henry Solomon Hendricks.
    - Henry S. and Rosalie (Nathan) Hendricks: genealogical research and notes, 1931-1966; 8181 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      See Subseries IX.D. Rosalie Gomez (Nathan) Hendricks.
    - Aaron and Sarah Correa (parents of Rachel Brandon, grandparents of Emma Brandon Hendricks), 1818-1838; 8182 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Joseph Brandon, 1864-1905; 8184 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Joseph and Rachel (Correa) Brandon (parents of Emma Brandon Hendricks), 1829-1884; 8183 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Alice (Hendricks) Brandon (daughter of Uriah II and Fanny, wife of Harmon II, wife of Edward), 1884; 8185 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Brandon family, 1846-1935; 8186 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Brandon family: genealogical research and notes, 1931; 8187 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Edwin Einstein (husband of Fanny Hendricks Einstein): correspondence and business records, 1880-1903; 8188 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Edwin Einstein: correspondence and business records, 1892; 8189 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Edwin Einstein: correspondence and business records, 1896-1897; 8190 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Edwin Einstein: newspaper clippings, 1890s; 8191 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - J.L. Florance, 1851, 1867; 8193 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Edwin Einstein: newspaper clippings, 1890s; 8192 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Ethel Hendricks: DAR certificate, 1911; 8286 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 14)
    - Joseph and Rachel Brandon items, 1836, 1836, 1884; 8287 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 15)
    - Henry S. and Rosalie Nathan Hendricks ancestry (original and photostat); Ethel Hendricks diplomas, 1905, 1907; 1920s; 8293 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 15)
    - Emma Brandon: notebook, 1846 September - 1847; 8194 (Volume 19)
    - Emma Brandon: notebook, 1847 September - 1848 March; 8195 (Volume 20)
    - Joseph Brandon: ledger re estate, 1890-1905; 8196 (Volume 21)
    - Joseph Brandon: notebook, Undated; 8197 (Volume 22)
  - Subseries V.F. Gomez Family, 7984
    For additional Gomez family material see Subseries IX.D. Rosalie Gomez (Nathan) Hendricks.
    - Aaron Lopez Gomez, 1829; 8198 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Charlotte (Hendricks) Gomez (sister of Harmon Hendricks, wife of Benjamin), 1838-1839; 8199 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Hetty Matilda Gomez (daughter of Benjamin and Charlotte), 1893-1895; 8200 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Isaac Gomez, 1815, 1909; 8201 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Letter to Aaron Lopez Gomez, 1829; 8288 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 15)
    - Indentures, 1809; 8299 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 16)
  - Subseries V.G. Families H-L, 7985
    - Zipporah Hart (daughter of Bernard and Catherine [Brett] Hart), 1854-1859; 8202 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Henry S. Hendricks, 1891; 8203 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Justina L. (Hendricks): will, 1906; 8204 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Henry, deCordova & Hendricks Co.: articles of co-partnership, 1859; 8205 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Isaacs family (Joshua and Solomon): copies of correspondence, 1744-1845; 8206 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - David Judah, 1827; 8207 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Amelia B. Lazarus (daughter of Tobias I. Tobias; sister of Uriah Hendricks, II; wife of Jacob), 1892-1897; 8208 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Isaac Leeser, 1838-1840, 1917; 8209 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Benjamin Jacobs: will, Undated; 8290 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 16)
  - Subseries V.H. Nathan Family, 7986
    For additional Nathan family material see Subseries IX.F. Nathan family.
    - Seixas Nathan, 1836; 8210 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Gershom Nathan: notebook, 1840s; 8260 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      See Subseries IX.F. Nathan family.
    - Gershom Nathan: scrapbook & ledger, 1840-1841; 200939 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Edgar J. Nathan, 1882-1952; 8212 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      See Subseries IX.G. Edgar Joshua Nathan Sr. and family.
    - Rosalie (Gomez) Nathan, 1851-1853; 8213 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Benjamin Nathan, 1870; 8214 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Miriam (Hendricks) Nathan (daughter of Henry and Harriet, wife of Gratz), 1877; 8215 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Clarence S. Nathan, 1924; 8216 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      For additional material see Subseries IX.F. Nathan family.
    - Gershom Nathan: notebook, 1840-1841; 8211 (Volume 23)
  - Subseries V.I. Families S-W, 7987
    - Seixas family: copies of historical notes, Undated; 8217 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Tobias family: wills and miscellaneous genealogical material, 1857-1938; 8218 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Rachel Waag (aunt of Harmon Hendricks, wife of Abraham), 1803-1809; 8219 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Various Hendricks-related families: miscellaneous wills and other documents, 1713-1814; 8220 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Rachel Waag, Power of Attorney, 1803 February; 8289 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 16)
  - Subseries V.J. Notes, Clippings, Correspondence, and Visual Material, 7988
    - Hendricks family correspondence with Shearith Israel, 1825-1838; 8221 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Hendricks family cemetery plots at Shearith Israel, 1928; 8222 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings, late 1800s-1967; 8223 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Genealogical research and notes, charts, and coat-of-arms, 1894-1932, undated; 8224 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings culled from the collection, 1806-1928; 8225 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Gomez, DaCosta, Brandon, de Leon Hayes, Solis, Fonseca families: genealogical information, 1883-1931, undated; 8226 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Three unidentified images: daguerreotype of girl aged approx. 5 years, two ambrotypes of one girl aged approx. 10 years, [1850s]; 8227 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Samuel Brouwer, Bernard Hart, Aaron Henry indentures; Aaron Hendricks genealogy, 1797,1815, 1816, 1931; 8298 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 16)
- Series VI. Related Families Business Records (1821-1869), 7903
  - Subseries VI.A. Tobias Brothers, Merchants (1821-1859), 8234
    The subseries contains material relating to the watch and wine trade of Tobias I. Tobias and his sons, Henry and Charles, who were the father and brothers, respectively, of Fanny Tobias Hendricks, wife of Uriah Hendricks, II. It includes loose correspondence, invoices, and other business records organized chronologically by person and subject.
    - Henry Tobias: cloth orders, 1821-1856; 8228 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Henry and Charles Tobias: business correspondence, 1831-1853; 8229 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Tobias I. Tobias: wine orders, 1832-1859; 8230 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Henry and Charles Tobias: watch orders (folder 1 of 2), 1839-1846; 8231 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Henry and Charles Tobias: watch orders (folder 2 of 2), 1839-1846; 8232 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Henry and Charles Tobias: invoices received, other items, 1839-1856; 8233 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Invoices, business records, 1838-1839; 8291 (Box OS Small, Folder Y-Hendricks 16)
  - Subseries VI.B. Tobias, Hendricks and Company (1859-1869), 8235
    The subseries contains material relating to the mercantile trade of Tobias, Hendricks and Company, a partnership between Thomas Jefferson Tobias and Francis Hendricks, son of Uriah Hendricks, II. It includes loose correspondence and invoices organized chronologically, and a letterbook containing 465 letters
    - Correspondence and business records, 1859-1868; 8236 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Letterbook, 1865-1866; 8237 (Volume 24)
- Series VII. Printed Material (1796-1875), 1796-1895; 7904
  The series includes newspaper clippings, brochures, pamphlets, advertisements, invoices, and other printed material, organized chronologically.
  - Tontine Coffee House constitution, 1796; 8238 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - New-York Price-Current, 1803-1812; 8239 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - New-York City-Hall Recorder, 1817-1818; 8240 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Advertisements and booklets for non-Hendricks businesses, 1817-1866; 8241 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Daily Whig, Examiner, The Hornet, 1823-1846; 8242 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "Proceedings of the General Convention of Agriculturists and Manufacturers and Others", 1827 July 30; 8243 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Invoices for non-Hendricks businesses, 1835-1869; 8244 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - School geography atlas, 1838; 8245 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Oration by William B. Reed, Philadelphia, 1849; 8246 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Life insurance policy, Francis W. Gardner, 1871; 8247 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Brochure: "Incidents in the emigration work of the Children's Aid Society", 1875; 8248 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Series VIII. Manuscript, Copper for America, by Maxwell Whiteman (1971), 7905
  The series contains several drafts and the finished manuscript for Maxwell Whiteman's 1971 book, Copper for America, on the Hendricks family and its role in the American copper industry. The N-YHS Library also holds the published book, Copper for America: The Hendricks Family and a National Industry, 1755-1939, under call number HD9539.C7 U58.
  - Draft, pages 157-236, Published 1971; 8249 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Draft, Chapters 1 and 2, Published 1971; 8250 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Draft, Chapter 3, Published 1971; 8251 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Draft, Chapter 4, Published 1971; 8252 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Draft, Chapter 5 and Epilogue, Published 1971; 8253 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Edited manuscript, pp. 1-177, Published 1971; 8254 (Volume 25)
- Series IX. Hendricks and Related Families Supplement (1790-1976), 201743; 3.77 Linear feet (10 boxes)
  Like Series V, this supplemental series contains the personal papers of members of several generations of the Hendricks family and other families related to them by marriage, in the form of personal papers, correspondence, wills, marriage contract, and other religious and legal documents, photographs, and memorabilia. It also contains genealogical research and notes, and other background information.
  The records describe the Hendricks family's involvement in the social, religious, and economic life of the city. Member of the Hendricks family were leaders of Congregation Shearith Israel, the Jewish Benevolent Society, and the American Jewish Historical Society. Given the extent of intermarriage with other prominent New York Jewish families and the Hendricks's position as community leaders, the material contains a wealth of information on the New York Jewish community and New York society in general, from the late eighteenth to the mid-twentieth centuries.
  For additional material see Series V. Hendricks and Related Families Personal Papers (1713-1966).
  Series IX is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries IX.A. Early Hendricks family material
  Subseries IX.B. Lilian (Henry) Hendricks
  Subseries IX.C. Henry Solomon Hendricks
  Subseries IX.D. Rosalie Gomez (Nathan) Hendricks
  Subseries IX.E. Hays and Solis families
  Subseries IX.F. Nathan family
  Subseries IX.G. Edgar Joshua Nathan Sr. and family
  Subseries IX.H. Printed material
  - Subseries IX.A. Early Hendricks family material, 201744
    This subseries contains miscellaneous letters, receipts, property agreements, and genealogical material relating to various early Hendricks family members.
    The documents in Subseries IX.A are in chronological order.
    - Uriah Hendricks [I] (1737–1798): agreement with George Ulshoeffer for a rental property on Nassau Street, Manhattan, 1790 February 5; 201764 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Uriah Hendricks [I] (1737–1798): genealogical and biographical material, 1791–1792; 201763 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Includes typed transcripts of two letters dated 1791 and 1792.
    - Harmon [II] and Frances (Isaacs) Hendricks: ketubah (marriage contract), 1800; 201765 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      In Hebrew; includes manuscript and typed translations.
    - John G. Bogert [?] and Brockholst [?] Livingston: agreement for property at 76 Broad Street, Manhattan., 1804 February 18; 201766 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Harmon Hendricks [II] (1771–1838): receipt for tuition of son, Henry, 1816 January 9; 201767 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      With a letter from Rabbi David de Sola Pool (1885–1970) returning the receipt to Mr. and Mrs. Henry S. Hendricks, [16?] September 1952.
    - Harmon Hendricks: letter from grandfather, [?] Nathan, 1851 July 3; 201768 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Hendricks and related families: correspondence and receipts regarding Congregation Shearith Israel, 1805–1866; 201769 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Joshua and Emma (Brandon) Hendricks: marriage invitation, 1857 January 28; 201770 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Edgar Hendricks (d. 1894): obituary (newspaper clipping), 1894 December 15; 201772 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Biographical/Historical Note
      Son of Joshua and Emma (Brandon) Hendricks.
    - Henry Harmon Hendricks (ca. 1860–1904): obituary (typescript), 201771 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Subseries IX.B. Lilian (Henry) Hendricks, 201782
    Correspondence (1876-1925) and a travel diary (1901-1924) of Lilian (Henry) Hendricks (1858-1924), widow of Edgar Hendricks (d. 1894) and mother of Henry Solomon Hendricks (1892-1959) [see Subseries IX.C]. She was for many years on the Board of Directors of the Sisterhood of Congregation Shearith Israel, and also served as its treasurer.
    Subseries IX.B is largely correspondence, and is arranged chronologically. A travel diary covering 1901-1924 is filed after the sequence.
    - Correspondence, 1876–1910; 201773 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Letters in French, from her school principal; includes rewards of merit.
    - Correspondence, 1879–1887; 201774 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Edgar and Lilian (Henry) Hendricks: marriage invitation, 1890 November 5; 201775 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1903–1904, 1907; 201776 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Mostly letters from son, Henry Solomon Hendricks (1892–1959). Includes an 1899 U.S. dollar bill silver certificate.
    - Correspondence, 1914, 1918; 201777 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1915–1916; 201778 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      Notes and letters of congratulation on engagement and marriage of son, Henry Solomon Hendricks (1892–1959) to Rosalie Gomez Nathan (1894–1986).
    - Correspondence, 1921 May–June; 201779 (Box 22, Folder 17)
      Notes and letters of congratulation on birth of granddaughter, Ruth Hendricks (later Mrs. Hyman A. Schulson).
    - Correspondence, 1925; 201780 (Box 22, Folder 18)
      Includes what appears to be her final letter to her son, Henry Solomon Hendricks (1892–1959), dated 18 June 1925, and an obituary.
    - Travel diary, 1901–1924; 201781 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Subseries IX.C. Henry Solomon Hendricks, 201746
    Henry Solomon Hendricks (1892-1959), son of Edgar and Lilian (Henry) Hendricks, was an attorney who served on the boards of a number of Jewish social and philanthropic organizations, among them the American Jewish Historical Society and Jewish Family Service Association. A lifelong member of Congregation Shearith Israel (as were his ancestors back to the founding of the synagogue), he served it as a trustee from 1923 until his death, and as president (parnas) in 1927-1930, 1934-1935, and 1939-1951, and honorary president from 1952.